Partial Inventory of the E. Thomas Wood Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
E. Thomas Wood papers
1939-2000
2000C114
Hoover Institution Archives
14 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box. (6 linear feet)
Writings, notes, correspondence, photocopies of government documents, books, other printed matter, photographs, and videotapes, relating to Jan Karski, the resistance movement and Jewish holocaust in Poland during World War II, and Jewish refugees in the Soviet Union. In part, used as research material for the book by E. T. Wood and Stanislaw M. Jankowski, Karski (New York, 1994). Digital copies of selected items also available.
Wood, E. Thomas, 1963-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American historian.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, notes, correspondence, photocopies of government documents, books, other printed matter, photographs, and videotapes, relating to Jan Karski, the resistance movement and Jewish holocaust in Poland during World War II, and Jewish refugees in the Soviet Union. In part, used as research material for the book by E. T. Wood and Stanislaw M. Jankowski, Karski (New York, 1994).
Karski, Jan, 1914-2000; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Refugees.; Video tapes.; World War, 1939-1945--Jews.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945--Soviet Union.; World War, 1939-1945--Underground movements.
- Sound recordings, 1992-2000; 29 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - Jan Karski interview, 3 October 1993
    Access
    In English and Polish. Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007256
  - Jan Karski interview, 27 February 1992
    In English. Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007304
  - Jan Karski interview, February 1992
    In English. Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007305
  - Jan Karski interview, 15-16 June 1992
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007306
  - Jan Karski interview, 2 October - 13 December 1992
    Parts 1-6 recorded on 2 October 1992; Part 6 recorded on 13 December 1992. Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007309
  - Jan Karski interview, 3 October 1992
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007310
  - Jan Karski discussing Wiesel, 25-28 February 1993
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007311
  - Jan Karski interview, April - 8 May 1993
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007312
  - Jan Karski interview, 4 August 1993
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007315
  - Landau interview and other assorted conversations, 5 October - 1 December 1993
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007316
  - Media appearances by Jan Karski, 26 October - 19 December 1994
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007317
    Scope and Contents note
    Side A: BBC World Service "Outlook," 19 December 1994. Side B: Karski on VA Radio program, part 2.
  - Jan Karski at the Temple, Nashville, Tennessee, 19 April 1996
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007318
  - Radio portrait, 24 October 1997
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007319
    Sleeve label reads: NDR 4 24 OCT. 1997 18:30-19:00 "FORUM 4' BY THOMAS HESTERMANN ---- SIDE 2: "AM A[?]END VORGESTENT" WDR3 (KOLN), CORNELIA BEOEL
  - National Public Radio obituary for Jan Karski, 15 July 2000
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007320
  - Jan Karski featured on Bridges: A Liberal/Conservative Dialogue with Larry Josephson, circa 1994-1997
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007321
  - Sound recordings, 2 June - 19 August 1993
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007322
  - Jan Karski interview and other material, 28 May - 17 September 1993
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007324
  - Jan Karski telephone interview, 31 January and 28 March 1993
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0007325
  - Chaim Shapiro interview in Baltimore, 18 March 1996
    Use copy reference number: 2000c114_a_0010495
- Rest of collection not yet described (Box 2-15)